# Satish Koogu

# **Assistant Sales Manager**

#### Contact

2/3 Hamsadwani-Nilaya, Whitefield, Bangalore, KA 560066





#### **Key Skills**

**Confidence** – maintaining a positive attitude.

**Resilience** – communicating with conviction.

**Active listening** – Understand the customer's needs.

**Rapport Building** – Selling your personality.

**Entrepreneurial spirit** – Continual self-improvement.

### Strengths

**Go-Getter:** Energetic and determined to achieve my goals.

Results/Detail Oriented: Dedicated to the completion of tasks in a timely manner.

Organized and Self-Disciplined: Take full responsibility to deliver my work on time and find the right balance between quality work and quality time with my family at home.

## **Objective**

Assistant sales manager with a demonstrated record of success as a sales team leader with exceptional relationship-building skills, persuasive communication style, and motivational approach. Highly experienced with the sales market and proven talent in learning new products, services, and skills quickly.

Hardworking and driven sales management professional equipped to revitalize sales operations and align procedures to maximize profits and client acquisition. Successful at improving sales procedures to streamline and strengthen processes. A multifaceted leader with an analytical and diligent approach to building and leading strong teams.

#### **Experience**

#### **Total Environment Building Systems**

Assistant Sales Manager | Bengaluru - October 2019 - Present

- Developed loyal and highly satisfied customer base through proactive management of team customer service strategies.
- Strengthened promotional strategies to drive customer engagement and boost sales.
- Selling Experience of Residential Projects at the Prime location of City.
- Increased sales revenues by promoting complementary products and educating customers about promotions.
- Handling customer queries for better customer satisfaction. Identifying prospective clients, generating business from the existing clientele to achieve business targets.
- Interacting with the clients and channel partners on a regular basis & providing redress to all their queries, complaints & handling all client relation.
- Increased sales by driving operational efficiencies and building excellent customer rapport.
- Planned team-building exercises to increase employee performance and job satisfaction.
- Mentored sales team in applying effective sales techniques and delivering top-notch customer service.
- Handled customer relations issues, enabling quick resolution, and client satisfaction.
- Attended industry shows, conventions, and other meetings with primary mission of expanding market opportunities.

#### First Advantage Global Operating Centre

Accounts Specialist | Bengaluru - July 2014 - August 2019

- Produced month-end closing reports and provided actionable suggestions on remittance for quick resolution.
- Reached out to vendors and customers to verify information and follow up on client issues.
- Processed invoices with efficiency and accuracy, resulting in decreased discrepancies.
- Streamlined productivity by decreasing time-wasting tasks and helping supervisors.
- Investigated daily variances and corrected errors to resolve discrepancies.
- Sent billing protocols weekly to vendors and ensured the vendors followed the same.
- Processed credit memos.
- Regularly monitored accounts to ensure all invoices are paid in a timely manner.
- Processed payment to vendors and sent remittances.

#### First European Infotech

Team Leader | Verna, Goa - January 2014 - June 2014

- To Manage the Credit Control team ensuring that debtor days are as per the Credit terms.
- Oversee credit limits granted to ensure that they are regularly reviewed in line with current risk assessments and business needs.
- Regularly communicate and work with the sales team to find solutions to potential credit risk problems.
- Regularly review work produced by the Team to ensure consistent standards are achieved and Credit Control procedures are being adhered to
- Drove operational improvements which resulted in savings and improved profit margins.
- Worked with team to identify areas of improvement and devised solutions based on findings.
- Monitored team performance and provided constructive feedback to increase productivity and maintain quality standards.

#### **Dell International Services**

Financial Administrative | Bengaluru - July 2011 - October 2013

- Monitored accounts for compliance with established payment plans and flagged non-compliances.
- Maintained a high volume of calls and met the demands of a busy and productive group.
- Trained new team members on scripts, company services, and collection strategies.
- Delivered exceptional customer service on collection calls and maintained calm.
- Advised customers of alternative actions and strategies for debt repayment and attempted to avoid adversarial communications.
- Worked with customers to create debt repayment plans based on current financial conditions.

#### [24]7.ai

Senior Sales Associate | Bengaluru - February 2006 - May 2011

- Met or exceeded sales objectives on a consistent basis to drive company growth.
- Trained new sales personnel on company policies, customer acquisition strategies, and successful sales techniques.
- Reported sales data to upper management for review.
- Monitored sales team performance and provided constructive feedback.
- Led sales team to exceed quarterly sales goals.
- Achieved and exceeded sales goals through dedication to identifying and pursuing new opportunities.
- Provided exceptional customer service to foster client loyalty and satisfaction.

#### **Personal Info**

Date of Birth: 03rd March 1986
Current CTC: 8 Lac/annum
Current Location: Bangalore
Work Location: Willing to Relocate

Permanent address: GF-2, Navelim Salcete, South Goa - 403707

#### Language

English, Hindi, Konkani, Kannada, Telegu, Marathi

#### **Education:**

2011-06 -	Bachelor of Commerce: Commerce
2014-12	Bangalore University - Bangalore, Karnataka
2001-06 - 2003-05	<b>High School Diploma</b> ITI Farmagudi College - Ponda, Goa
2000-06 - 2001-03	Higher Secondary: SSC St' Mary's High School - Varca, Goa

#### **Hobbies**

"I like learning new skills and recently I have been interested in exploring different places as they help me explore new cultures around the world. I started exploring villages and cuisines to learn about their food and method of cooking. I generally spend my weekends focusing on exploring new places and their food cultures."

#### References

Arvind Kumar Tiwari:

Phone - +91 98868 85214

Email - ak84\_tiwari@yahoo.com